Guide to the Joshua A. Fishman Papers
Department of Special Collections
- Series 2 J. A. Fishman Published and Unpublished Works, 1940s-1990s
  - The Sociology of English as a Second Language (Box 59, Folder 8)
  - The Sociology of Jewish Languages from a General Sociolinguistic Point of View (Box 59, Folder 9)
  - The Sociology of Jewish Languages from the Perspective of the General Sociology of Language: A Preliminary Formulation (Box 60, Folder 1)
  - The Sociology of Jewish Languages (Box 60, Folder 2)
  - The Sociology of Language (Box 60, Folder 3)
  - The Sociology of Language and Second Language Teaching (Box 60, Folder 4)
  - The Sociology of Language: An Interdisciplinary Social Science Approach to Language and Society (Box 60, Folder 5)
  - The Sociology of Language in Israel (Box 60, Folder 6)
  - The Sociology of Language: Yesterday, Today and Tomorrow (Box 60, Folder 7)
  - The Sociology of Yiddish (Box 60, Folder 8)
  - The Sociology of Yiddish after the Holocaust: Status, Needs and Possibilities (Box 60, Folder 9)
  - Some Contrasts Between Linguistically Homo/Heterogeneous Polities (Box 61, Folder 1)
  - Some Current Research Needs in the Psychology of Testimony (Box 61, Folder 2)
  - Some Measures of the Interaction between Language, Domain and Semantic Dimensions in Bilinguals (Box 61, Folder 3)
  - Some Social and Psychological Determinants of Intergroup Relations in Changing Neighborhoods (Box 61, Folder 4)
  - Some Social-Psychological Theory for Selecting and Guiding College Students (Box 61, Folder 5)
  - Some Statistical Findings on the Social-Psychology of the American High School (Box 61, Folder 6)
  - Some Studies of Language Attitude in Israel (Box 61, Folder 7)
  - Some Things Learned; Some Things Yet to Learn (Box 61, Folder 8)
  - DI SOTSIYOLOGIYE FUN YIDISH IN AMERIKE: 1960-1970 (Box 61, Folder 9)
  - Southern City (Box 61, Folder 10)
  - Spanish Language Resources of the United States: Some Preliminary Findings (Box 61, Folder 11)
  - Special Issue of "The Bilingual Family Newsletter": Yiddish (Box 61, Folder 12)
  - The Spread of English [1 of 2] (Box 61, Folder 13)
  - The Spread of English [2 of 2] (Box 62, Folder 1)
  - The Spread of English as a New Perspective for the Study of "Language Maintenance and Language Shift" (Box 62, Folder 2)
  - The Spread of English: A Worldwide Factor in the Making and Breaking of Bilingualism (Box 62, Folder 3)
  - The Spread of English - unpublished manuscript (Box 62, Folder 4)
  - Standard vs "Dialect" in Bilingual Education: An Old Problem in a New Context (Box 62, Folder 5)
  - Status Planning for Endangered Languages (Box 63, Folder 1)
  - The Status and Prospects of Bilingualism in the United States (Box 63, Folder 2)
  - Strategies des langues juives (Box 63, Folder 3)
  - The Strategy of Yiddish (Box 63, Folder 4)
  - Studies in Modern Jewish Social History (Box 63, Folder 5)
  - Studies of Language as an Aspect of Ethnicity and Nationalism (A Bibliographic Introduction) (Box 63, Folder 6)
  - Studies on Polish Jewry (Box 63, Folder 7)
  - A Study of Language Attitudes (Box 63, Folder 8)
  - Subsequent Written Comment by JAF on Haugen's Paper (Box 63, Folder 9)
  - Survey of Jewish Education in America (Box 63, Folder 10)
  - A Systematization of the Whorfian Hypothesis (Box 63, Folder 11)
  - Testing--Its Relationship to Teaching and Learning (Box 64, Folder 1)
  - Theoretical Issues and Problems in the Sociolinguistic Enterprise (Box 64, Folder 2)
  - The Third Century of Non-English Language Maintenance and Non-Anglo Ethnic Maintenance in the United States of America (Box 64, Folder 3)
  - Three Brief Talks (Box 64, Folder 4)
  - Three Dilemmas of Organized Efforts to Reverse Language Shift (Box 64, Folder 5)
  - A TIKN-TOYES FUN PROFESOR FISHMAN (Box 64, Folder 6)
  - DER TKHIYES-HAMEYSIM FUN DI FRIZN (Box 64, Folder 7)
  - Toward Multilingualism as an International Desideratum in Government, Business and the Professions (Box 64, Folder 8)
  - TRADITSIYONELE GEZELSHAFTLEKHE ROL FUN YIDISH (Box 64, Folder 9)
  - Transitional, Maintenance or a Third Alternative (Box 64, Folder 10)
  - Trici Aspekt Vorfove Misli: Ethnolingvisticka Raznolikost kao Dobrobit Drustvenih Zajednica Sveta (Box 64, Folder 11)
  - The Truth, the Whole Truth and Nothing but the Truth about Language and Culture (Box 64, Folder 12)
  - The Tshernovits Conference Revisited: The First World Conference for Yiddish, 85 Years Later (Box 64, Folder 13)
  - TSI DARF AMERIKE AN OFITSYELE SHPRAKH? (Box 64, Folder 14)
  - TSI IZ NOKH DO A HOFENUNG FAR YIDISH IN AMERIKE? (Box 64, Folder 15)
  - TSI KEN EYN SHPRAKH FARMOEN TSVEY NORMES? DER NORVEGISHER FAL (Box 65, Folder 1)
  - TSULIB VOS DARFN MIR NOKH YIDISH OYKH? (AN ENTFER AF DER FRAGE, VOS S'FREGT DI ORGANIZATSIYONELE FIRERSHAFT FUN AMERIKANER YIDNTUM (Box 65, Folder 2)
  - TSU MAKS VAYNRAYKHS ZI STN YORTSAYT (Box 65, Folder 3)
  - DER TSUSHTAYER FUN VELTLEKHKAYT TSUM YIDISHN LEBN (Box 65, Folder 4)
  - TSVEYSHPRAKHIKAYT IN A YIDISHER SHUL (EYNIKE KORELATN UN NIT-KORELATN) (Box 65, Folder 5)
  - TSVEYSHPRAKHIKE DERTSIYUNG IN AMERIKE (Box 65, Folder 6)
  - UMZISTER AGMES-NEFESH? (Box 65, Folder 7)
  - U.S. Census Data on Mother Tongues: Review, Extrapolations and Predictions (Box 65, Folder 8)
  - Unsolved Criterion Problems in the Selection of College Students (Box 65, Folder 9)
  - The Use of Hebrew Loanwords in Spoken German in Two Bilingual Communities (Box 65, Folder 10)
  - The Use of Quantitative Techniques to Predict College Success (Box 65, Folder 11)
  - The Use of Tests for Admission to College: The Next Fifty Years (Box 65, Folder 12)
  - The Uses of Sociolinguistics (Box 65, Folder 13)
  - The Validity of Census Data in Bilingualism in a Puerto Rican Neighborhood (Box 65, Folder 14)
  - Varieties of Ethnicity and Varieties of Language Consciousness (Box 65, Folder 15)
  - Varieties of Literary Languages: New World Perspectives (Box 65, Folder 16)
  - VEGN DEM PROYEKT VI TSU TRANSKRIBIRN AF ENGLISH YIDISHE NEMEN UN TITLEN FUN BIKHER (Box 66, Folder 1)
  - VEGN DI MUSTERVERK FUN DER YIDISHER LITERATUR (Box 66, Folder 2)
  - VEGN HEYLN ZIKH (Box 66, Folder 3)
  - VEGN MAYN MAMES KINDERYORN (Box 66, Folder 4)
  - A VERTERBUKH FUN FOLKLOR, MITOLOGIYE UN LEGENDE (Box 66, Folder 5)
  - DI VEYNIKER BANUTSTE SHPRAKHN (Box 66, Folder 6)
  - VI DARF MEN FAYERN YOMIM-NOYROYIM IN DI SHULN? (Box 66, Folder 7)
  - VIFL DARF MEN ONGEBN DEM KVAL UN BAY VOS (Box 66, Folder 8)
  - DI VIKHTIKAYT FUN A YIDISHER DERTSIYUNG FAR AMERIKANER (Box 66, Folder 9)
  - VOS HEYST YIDISH LEBN? (Box 66, Folder 10)
  - VOS HOT DI YIDISHE LITERATUR GETON FAR DER YIDISHER SHPRAKH? (Box 66, Folder 11)
  - VOS IZ DER SHAYKHES TSVISHN SHPRAKH UN KULTUR? (Box 66, Folder 12)
  - VOS KEN ZAYN DI FUNKTSIYE FUN YIDISH IN YISROYEL FAR DI NAYE DOYRES? (Box 66, Folder 13)
  - VOS VET VAYTER ZAYN? VOS VET UNDZ NOKH BLAYBN? (Box 66, Folder 14)
  - VOS VET ZAYN MIT DZSHUDEZMO UN MUGRABISH? (Box 66, Folder 15)
  - What Can Mass-Testing Programs Do for and to the Pursuit of Excellence in American Education (Box 66, Folder 16)
  - What Do We Know about Language Planning? (Box 66, Folder 17)
  - What Has the Sociology of Language to Say to the Teacher? (Box 66, Folder 18)
  - What Is Happening to Spanish on the US Mainland? (Box 66, Folder 19)
  - What is Reversing Language Shift (RSL) and How Can It Succeed? (Box 67, Folder 1)
  - What Should We Do for Languages and Language Groups in the USA in Order to Build a Decent Multi-ethnic Society? (Box 67, Folder 2)
  - What We Know and What We Need to Know about Philadelphia's Ethnic Groups (Box 67, Folder 3)
  - Who Needs Bilingual Education and Why: A Guest Editorial (Box 67, Folder 4)
  - Who Speaks What Languages to Whom and When? (Box 67, Folder 5)
  - The Whorfian Hypothesis in 1975: A Sociolinguistic Re-evaluation (Box 67, Folder 6)
  - The Whorfian Hypothesis: Varieties of Valuation, Confirmation and Dis-Confirmation (Box 67, Folder 7)
  - Whorfianism of the Third Kind: Ethnolinguistic Diversity as a Worldwide Societal Asset (Box 67, Folder 8)
  - Why Did Yiddish Change? (Box 67, Folder 9)
  - Why This Directory Is Needed and How to Help Improve It (Box 67, Folder 10)
  - Witnesses and Testimony: A Social Problem in Need of Social Research (Box 67, Folder 11)
  - Will Foreign Languages Still Be Taught in the Year 2000? (Box 68, Folder 1)
  - Word-naming and Usage Scores For a Sample of Yiddish-English Bilinguals (Box 68, Folder 2)
  - Written Spanish in the United States: An Analysis of the Spanish in the Ethnic Press (Box 68, Folder 3)
  - DI YERUSHOLAYIMER VELT-KONFERENTS FAR YIDISH UN YIDISHER KULTUR FUN A SOTSIYOLINGVISTISHN KUKVINKL (Box 68, Folder 4)
  - Yiddish (Box 68, Folder 5)
  - Yiddish and Loshn-Koydesh in Traditional Ashkenaz: Problems in the Societal Allocation of Macro-Functions (Box 68, Folder 6)
  - Yiddish and Voting Rights in New York State: 1915 and 1921 [1 of 2] (Box 68, Folder 7)
  - Yiddish and Voting Rights in New York State: 1915 and 1921 [2 of 2] (Box 68, Folder 8)
  - Yiddish Dictionaries Through the Centuries (Box 68, Folder 9)
  - Yiddish in America [1 of 2] (Box 69, Folder 1)
  - Yiddish in America [2 of 2] (Box 69, Folder 2)
  - Yiddish in Israel (Box 69, Folder 3)
  - Yiddish Today--Yiddish for the People (Box 69, Folder 4)
  - Yiddish: Turning to Life [1 of 3] (Box 69, Folder 5)
  - Yiddish: Turning to Life [2 of 3] (Box 69, Folder 6)
  - Yiddish: Turning to Life [3 of 3] (Box 70, Folder 1)
  - "Yiddish Watching": Keeping Your Eye on the Ball (Box 70, Folder 2)
  - YIDISH BAY DI KHAREYDIM: FRISHE KOYKHES UN NAYE TSORES (Box 70, Folder 3)
  - YIDISHE KEMPN IN AMERIKE (Box 70, Folder 4)
  - YIDISH IN YESHIVE-UNIVERSITET UN A SIMKHE FUN HASHIVAS-AVEYDE (Box 70, Folder 5)
  - YIDISH--MAYN ERSHTE HEYM (Box 70, Folder 6)
  - YIDISH, MODERNIZATSIYE UN REETNIFIKATSIYE: AN ERNSTER UN FAKTNDIKER TSUGANG TSU DER ITSTIKER PROBLEMATIK (Box 70, Folder 7)
  - DI YIDISHE SVIVE UN DI INTERNATSIYONALE INTELEKTUELE SVIVE (Box 70, Folder 8)
  - YIDISH UN ANDERE NATSIYONALE SHPRAKHN IN AMERIKE (Box 70, Folder 9)
  - YIDISH UN SHTIMREKHT IN NY--1915 UN 1921 (Box 70, Folder 10)
  - YIDISH UN YIDISHE SOTSIYOLINGVISTIK--TSVISHN YO UN NEYN (Box 70, Folder 11)
  - YIDISH UN VELTLEKHKAYT (Box 70, Folder 12)
  - YIDISHKAYT UN YIDISH IN MELBURN, OYSTRALIYE (Box 71, Folder 1)
  - DER YIVO IN AMERIKE: PROBLEMEN UN DERGREYKHUNGEN IN SHAYKHES MIT ZAYN MEHUS (Box 71, Folder 2)
  - DER YIVO IN AMERIKE/YIVO in America (Box 71, Folder 3)
  - Yivo: Thirty-Five Years in America (Box 71, Folder 4)
  - Yudel Mark (1897-1975) (Box 71, Folder 5)
  - An alphabetic card-file index containing: title, published/unpublished, date, publication (1967-1992) (Box 72)
  - JAF doctoral dissertation materials - notecards (Box 73, Folder 1)
  - JAF doctoral dissertation materials - defensse of dissertation (Box 73, Folder 2)
  - JAF doctoral dissertation materials - "Original data, Responses of Sample members to Bilinguality Relationships Scale, Bilingualism in a Yiddish School, Some Correlates and Non-Correlates" (Box 73, Folder 3)
- Series 3 J. A. Fishman Lectures and Talks ca. 1940-1992
  This series is multilingual (English/Yiddish/Spanish/Basque, mostly English/Yiddish) and is divided into two subseries. Subseries A Notes and Texts contains handwritten notes; research materials such as clippings, offprints, or statistical tables; a copy of the written presentation; and flyers, clippings, and other publicity materials. It is organized alphabetically by title. Subseries B contains audio and videocassettes and is organized by date. The audiocassettes are in sleeves; except for tapes from the Conference about the Basque Language (box 5 and 6), each tape has an individual entry in the listing. The language spoken is indicated by a letter, E for English, Y for Yiddish, Sp for Spanish, etc.
  - Subseries A Notes and Text
    - The Acquisition and Retention of Biliteracy: A Precis (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - AF A YONTEVDIKER TEME (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - AHAVES-YIDISH UN SINES-YIDISH IN MIZREKH-EYROPE (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Alternative Approaches to the Measurement and Description of Bilingualism (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - The Americanness of the Ethnic Mother Tongue School (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - American Psychology Today: What It Is and What It Is Not (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - AMERIKANER YIDNTUM VI AN OBYEKT FUN SOTSYAL VISNSHAFTLEKHER FORSHUNG: DERGREY KHUNGEN UN PROBLEMEN (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Anthropology and Linguistics (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - ARAYNFIR-VORT TSU A BARATUNG FUN YUGNT-KOMISIYE MITN SHOLEM ALEYKHEM FOLK INSTITUT (FORZITZER) (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Are Universities Necessary? (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Attitudes toward English in Israel (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Attracting a Following to High-Culture Functions for a Language of Everyday Life (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - AZA YOR AF UNDZ (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - A BAGRISUNG TSU MORDIKHE SHEKHTERN BAYM OYSTEYLN IM A PREMIYE (audio-cassette) (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - BAGRISUNG-VORT BAY DER SIMKHE LEKOVED DR. MORDKHE SHEKHTERS DRAY BIKHER (audio-cassette) (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - BAGRISUNG-VORT LEKOVED HARAV HERSHL SHEKHTERS 40 YOR IN MOSHOLU JEWISH CENTER (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Basic Issues in the Sociology of Language (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - BAY DER TROYER FARZAMLUNG LEZIKORN DER SHKITE IN MEDEM-SANITORIYE (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - BAYM OPNEMEN DI KHAYEM BEZ PREMIYE BAYM YIDISHN KULTUR KONGRES (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Benjamin Lee Whorf--Passing Experimentalist and Eternal Mystic (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Bilingual Education: A Cultural Right (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Bilingual Education and Ethnicity (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Bilingual Education: An International Sociological Perspective (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Bilingual Education: Ethnic Perspectives (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Bilingual Education for the Mainstream; A Rationale (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Bilingual Education: Intellectual, Emotional and Political Foundations (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Bilingual Education in the 80s (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Bilingual Education: Is It 'Good for the Jews'? (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Bilingual Education: Past, Present and Perfect (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Bilingual Education: A Theoretical Perspective (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Bilingual Education Under Ethnic Community Auspices in the United States (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Bilingual Higher Education: "Foundations, Policy and Practice"--Epilogue (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Bilingualism (audio-cassette) (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Bilingualism and Second Language Learning (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Bilingualism as a Critical National Resource (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Bilingualism in Education--Its Potential and Its Limits (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Bilingualism in Interdisciplinary Perspective (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Bilingualism in the Barrio (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Bilingualism Today and Tomorrow (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Biliteracy in Four Ethnic Community Schools (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - A BLIK HINTER DI KULISN FUN DER TSHERNOVITSER-SHPRAKH-KONFERENTS (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - BOREKH-HABO TSUM OYLE FUN SOVETN-FARBAND (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - The Breadth and Depth of English in the United States (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Broad Implications of the Research Project on Language Planning Processes (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Can Language Be Planned? (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Cartoons about Yiddish (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Cartoons about Yiddish and Hebrew (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - The Case for Ethnic Studies in American Higher Education (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Celebrating the Year of the Child (Keynote address) (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - The Challenge of Multilingualism Today: Two Prophets of Sociolinguistic Diversity (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - The Challenge of Multilingualism: Why Does It Worry Us? What Can It Give Us? (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Chanukah in Yiddish Song and Story (with GSF) (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Coming Home to Yiddish (audio-cassette) (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Comments on Chairing a Session at the Interamerican Congress of Psychology (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Classical Views of Language and Ethnicity and Their Traditional Modern Legacies (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Communication: Survival in the 21st Century (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - The Comparative Impact of Nationalism on Language Planning (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Concluding Remarks: Current Perspectives: Educational Symposium on Navajo Bilingual Linguistics (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - A Contemporary Assessment of Language Spread and Language Policy (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - The Content of Ethnolinguistic Consciousness (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Cross-Disciplinary Perspectives in Bilingual Education (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Cross Fertilization of English and Yiddish (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Cross Polity Perspective on the Importance of Linguistic Heterogeneity as a "Contributory Factor" in Civil Strife (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Cultural Conservation and Languages: America's Many Voices (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Current Perspectives: Educational Symposium on Navajo Bilingual Linguistics: Concluding Remarks (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Current Status and Future Prospects of the State of the Sociology of Language (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - The Current Status of Spanish and the Future of Spanish in the USA (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Deaf Children and the Socialization Process (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Defenders of Pluribus (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - DERHAYNTIKN, FARYIDISHN, FAREYNIKN (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - The Developing Nations: Multilingual and Multiproblem Polities (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - The Development of National Languages and Their Relation to the Language of Wider Communication in Developing Countries (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - The Development of Sociology (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Dialects and Literary Languages in the New World (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Dialects and Standard Language (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Dialect vs. Standard in Bilingual Education: An Old Problem in a New Context (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Dimensions in Bilingual Education (Introductory and Summary Remarks) (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Discussion of Conant's "Slums and Suburbs" (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Does Anyone Really Want Bilingual Education and Why? (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Does Our Language Mold Our Thinking? (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - DOKTER NOSN BIRNBOYM (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - DOR HOYLEKH VDOR BO (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - The Earliest Stages of Language Planning: Successes and Failures (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - The Earliest Stages of Language Planning: Successes and Failures, cont. (newspaper) (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - The Education of Language Minority Children in the Public Schools (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - The Emerging Picture of Modern American Jewry (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - An Empirical and Cross-National Study of Language Learning (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Empirical Explorations of Two Popular Assumptions: Interpolity Perspective on the Relationships between Linguistic Heterogeneity, Civil Strife and Per Capita Gross National Product (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - English and International Bilingualism (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - English Only and Bilingual Education: Tensions and Perspectives (audio-cassette) (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Ethnic Community Mother Tongue Schools in the USA (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Ethnic Community Schools in the USA: Instruments of More Than Literacy and Less Than Literacy (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Ethnic Identity--Visions and Revisions (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - The Ethnic Mother Tongue School (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Ethnic Revival (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - The Ethnic Revival in the United States (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - The Ethnic Revival in the United States: Implications for the Mexican-American Community (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Ethnic Revival of the Mid 60's to Mid 70's: Successes and Failures (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Ethnolinguistic Democracy: Varieties, Degrees and Limits (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Ethnolinguistic Dimensions in the Acquisition and Retention of Biliteracy--A Comparative Ethnography (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - ETNISHER UFLEB: UFSHTAYG UN YERIDE (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - DER ETNISHER UFSHTAYG FUN YIDISH IN DI 70-ER YORN (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - DI ETNISHE UFVAKHUNG FUN YIDISH (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Equity: Now, Then and Always (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - The Facts about Bilingualism (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Fifth Annual Conference on Perspectives on Bilingualism (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - FINF UN DRAYSIK YOR YIVO (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - FINF UN ZIBETSIK YOR NOKH DER TSHERNOVITSER KONFERENTS: NAYE FAKTN UN MEYNUNGEN (audio-cassette) (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - The "First Congress" Phenomenon: Some Tentative General Conclusions about the Earliest Stage of Language Planning (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - The Fourth Annual Conference on Perspectives on Bilingualism (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - From Hawaii to Israel--From the Ridiculous to the Sublime (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - The Future of Ethnic Languages: The Role of the School (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - The Future of Spanish in the USA (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - DI FUNKTSIYE FUN YIDISH IN YISROYEL FAR DI NAYE DOYRES (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - DOS GAYSTIKE PONIM FUN UNDZER DOR (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Greetings to Edmond Gordon on his 65th Birthday (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Greetings to the Membership of the Victorian Jewish Board of Deputies, Melbourne, Australia (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - GUTE MAYES VEGN YIDISH (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - HAFTIKAYT FUN SHPRAKH UN IBERRUK FUN SHPRAKH: YIDISH UN ANDERE IMIGRANTN-SHPRAKHN IN DI FAREYNIKTE SHTATN (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - DI HASHPOE FUN YDISH IN DER HAYNTIKER VELT (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - HASKORE NOKH DI YIDN FUN VILNE UN DI LIKVITATZIYE FUN VILNER GETO (audio-cassette) (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Has the Spread of English Continued? (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Hebrew in Sociolinguistic Perspective: Past Perfect and Future Indefinite (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - HESPED AF DER LEVAYE FUN MAYN MAMEN, SONYE FISHMAN (audio-cassette) (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - History and Context of Bilingual Education (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - History Is Being Created at Yeshiva University (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Honoring the Minority Languages and Folkways of America (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - How Are Corpus Planning Decisions Reached? (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - How Can We Measure the Roles Which a Bilingual's Languages Play in his Everyday Behavior? (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - How Have Franco-Americans Fared in Preserving the French Language in the United States? (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - How Language Minority Students Have Been Handled Throughout US Public Education History (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - How to Make Parent Involvement Work (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - How Yiddish Differs (audio-cassettes) (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - The Image of the American Jew (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - The Image of English (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - The Image of English and the International Sociolinguistic Balance of Power (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - The Impact of the Ethnic Revival on Mother Tongue and Language Use in the U.S.A. (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - In Praise of My Language--In Brooklyn (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - In Praise of My Language: Some Components of the Language Nationalism Belief System (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - International Colloquium on Language Planning: Synthesis (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - The International Nature of Bilingual Education (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - International Perspective in Bilingual Education (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - International Perspectives on Bilingual Education: Theoretical Dimensions and Concrete Cases (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - International Perspective on the Purported Debits of Linguistic Heterogeneity (audio-cassette) (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Inter-Polity Perspective on the Relationships between Linguistic Heterogeneity, Civil Strife and Per Capital Gross National Product (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Introductory Remarks for Psychologists for Peace Conference (Box 5, Folder 7)